Guide to the Ely and Walker Dry Goods Company records, 1883-1960
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Ely and Walker Dry Goods Company records, 1883-1960
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Ely and Walker Dry Goods Company (St. Louis, Mo.)
45 Items
Founded by David Davis Walker, Frank Ely, and others in 1883, based in St. Louis, Missouri. The company was acquired by Burlington Industries, Inc., in 1955.
Minutes of meetings of stockholders and of directors, financial statements, account books, and other legal and administrative documents of a firm that manufactured, converted, and distributed cotton fabrics and hosiery, whose general office was located in St. Louis, Missouri.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, collection may contain materials to which the Acknowledgment of Legal Responsibilities and Privacy Rights form applies. Patrons must sign this form before using this collection.
Also, all or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. Consequently, there may be a 24-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Ely and Walker Dry Goods Company Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1966.
Collection Overview
Minutes of meetings of stockholders and of directors, financial statements, account books, and other administrative documents of a firm manufacturing, converting, and distributing cotton fabrics, whose general office was located in St. Louis, Mo. Volumes have several identification numbers, the originals of which are marked with parentheses.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Burlington Industries, Inc
Cotton textile industry -- Records
Cotton textile industry -- Southern States
Textile industry -- Southern States
Industries -- Southern States
Saint Louis (Mo.)--Commerce
Contents of Collection
- Ely and Walker Dry Goods Company records, 1883-1960, (7 boxes; 15 volumes)
  The first group of ledgers has been boxed. The other volumes are arranged in rough chronological order, and are marked with the current library numbering sequence, and in parentheses, the original volume numbers.
  - Factories ledger: Sunbeam, 1934-1955 (Box 1)
  - Factories ledger: Paperbox, 1942-1948 (Box 1)
  - Factories ledger: Trunk, 1940-1953 (Box 1)
  - Factories ledger: Sweater, 1936-1952 (Box 2)
  - Factories ledger: Kennett, 1937-1959 (Box 2)
  - Factories ledger: Salem, 1944-1958 (Box 3)
  - Factories ledger: Paragould, 1937-1959 (Box 3)
  - Factories ledger: Hat, 1933-1953 (Box 4)
  - Factories ledger: Murphysboro, 1944-1949 (Box 4)
  - Factories ledger: Kitty Fisher, 1931-1949 (Box 4)
  - Factories ledger: Illmo, 1944-1959 (Box 5)
  - Factories ledger: Neckwear, 1939-1954 (Box 5)
  - Factories ledger: Lingerie, 1936-1953 (Box 6)
  - Factories ledger: Ann Foster, 1942-1953 (Box 6)
  - Factories ledger: Quincy, 1943-1959 (Box 6)
  - Factories ledger: Ledger, 1906-1920 (Box 7)
  - Documents, 1920-1927 and 1956, about federal tax cases (1918 to 1926) (Box 7)
  - Minutes, 1883-1906 (Volume 11 (1))
  - Financial statements, 1884-1906 (Volume 11 (1))
  - Minutes, 1906 (Volume 10 (2))
  - Financial statements, 1906 (Volume 10 (2))
  - Minutes, 1907-1913 (Volume 8 (3))
  - Financial statements, 1907-1913 (Volume 8 (3))
  - Minutes, 1913-1921 (Volume 9 (4))
  - Financial statements, 1913-1920 (Volume 9 (4))
  - Minutes, 1921-1928 (Volume 12 (5))
  - Financial statements, 1921-1927 (Volume 12 (5))
  - Minutes, 1928-1935 (Volume 3 (6))
  - Financial statements, 1927-1934 (Volume 3 (6))
  - Minutes, 1935-1944 (Volume 1 (7))
  - Financial statements, 1935-1943 (Volume 1 (7))
  - Minutes, 1944-1954 (Volume 2 (8))
  - Financial statements, 1943-1953 (Volume 2 (8))
  - Capital assets and depreciation, 1959-1960 (Volume 13 (9))
  - General ledger, 1959-1960 (Volume 14 (10))
  - Transfer ledger, 1938-1953 (Volume 15 (11))
  - Grabur Silk Mill, operating cost ledger, 1940-1944 (Volume 4)
  - Grabur Silk Mill, cost ledger, 1944-1948 (Volume 5)
  - Grabur Silk Mill, voucher register, 1944-1947 (Volume 6)
  - Grabur Silk Mill, voucher register, 1947-1948 (Volume 7)